(怒布拉岛  哥斯达黎加以西120英里)
放轻松
Relax.
这里的生物已经灭绝了
Anything in here would be dead by now.
找到她了
There she is...
暴虐霸王龙
the Indominus rex.
样本采集完毕
Specimen collected.
送上去了
Sent to the surface.
收到
Roger that.
空中一号 你可以起飞了
Air One, clear for takeoff.
- 开始追踪 - 收到
- Begin tracking. - Copy that.
- 开始行动 - 正在追踪
- Go, go! - Tracking on.
陆地一号 已获取
Land One, the asset is secure.
本次行动的目标物品
We got what we came for.
我们现在回来接你 关闭闸门吧
We're coming back for you. Close the doors.
海洋一号 我要关闭闸门了
Marine One, I got to close the gates.
快出来
Get out of there.
收到 我们马上出来
Understood. We're heading out.
(信号丢失)
海洋一号 我要关闭闸门了
Marine One, I need to close the gates.
报告你们的位置
Confirm position.
听到了吗 你们出来了吗
Can you hear me? Are you out?
海洋一号
Marine One?
- 伙计们 - 那是什么东西
- Guys? - What is that?
海洋一号 我关闭闸门了
Marine One, I'm closing the gates.
(正在关闭泻湖闸门)
伙计们 我在这外面淋雨呢
Seriously, guys, I'm kind of exposed out here.
海洋一号 报告你们的位置
Marine One, confirm you're out.
Marine One, confirm position.
能听到我吗 海洋一号 你们在哪
Can you hear me? Marine One, where are you?
- 他在那 - 快跑
- He's over there! - Now! Run!
看你后面
Look behind you!
我联系不上他们
I can't reach them!
- 快点 - 什么
- Come on! - What?!
怎么回事
What is going on?
我听不清楚你们在说什么
I can't hear you!
等等我 等等我 别走
Wait! Wait! Wait! Don't go!
(连接中断)
把绳梯扔给他
Throw him the ladder!
别丢下我
Don't go!
不
Oh! Oh, no!
不 等等我 别走
No! Wait! Don't go!
不 不
No, no! Aah!
不…
Oh-ho, ye...
我的天 不 不
Oh, God! No! No! Aah! Aah!
天啊 不
God, no!
我们要失速了 快割断绳梯
We're gonna stall! Cut it now!
- 给他个机会吧 - 我们都会死在这的
- Give him a chance! - We're gonna die here!
快点
Come on!
- 快点 - 不不不
- Come on! - No! No! No!
快割断绳梯
I said cut it!
不要啊
Don't do it! Aah!
太残忍了
It's horrible!
DNA样本到手了
DNA sample secure.
告诉老板 我们返程了
Tell the boss we're coming back home.
《侏罗纪世界2：殒落国度》
距离"侏罗纪世界"遭到摧毁已经过去了三年
Three years after the fall of Jurassic World,
围绕着怒布拉岛的争论仍然十分激烈
the debate over Isla Nublar rages on.
岛上长期休眠的火山
The island's long-dormant volcano,
已重新被归类为活火山
reclassified as active,
最近几个月来其活动明显增强
has shown considerable unrest in recent months.
目前地理学家预测 地球上最后一批恐龙
Geologists now predict an extinction-level event
将会迎来灭顶之灾
will kill off the last living dinosaurs on the planet.
自从2015年那场震惊世界的灾难发生之后
Since the disaster that shocked the world in 2015,
马斯拉尼公司已经支付了
the Masrani Corporation has paid out
超过8亿元的赔偿金
more than over 800 million in damages
用于处理事故幸存者提起的集体诉讼
to settle class-action lawsuits brought by survivors.
世界各地的民间组织纷纷动员起来
Activist groups have mobilized
在当代动物权益问题上
around the globe in what has become
表达自己的立场
the flashpoint animal rights issue of our time.
面对随时可能爆发的火山
With an eruption expected at any moment,
美国参议院成立了一个特别委员会
the U.S. Senate has convened a special committee
讨论这个严肃的伦理问题
to answer a grave moral question:
我们是否该给予恐龙和其他频危物种
Do dinosaurs deserve the same protections
同样的保护
given to other endangered species,
还是该任由它们灭绝
or should they be left to die?
我认为 我们应该让这些
I think that we should allow our, uh,
曾令世人惊叹的恐龙
magnificent and glorious dinosaurs...
随着火山爆发灭绝
to be taken out by the volcano.
这无异于谋杀犯
Murderer.
请保持安静
Silence, please.
虽然那样的结果令人痛心
As... as deeply sad as that would be...
但我们已经改变了大自然的进程
we altered the course of natural history.
这是纠正我们之前犯下的错误
This is a correction.
你的意思是这场天灾
Are you suggesting the Almighty is...
其实是上帝的安排
taking matters in his own hands?
参议员先生 恕我直言
Senator, with all due respect, God's not part
上帝并不是自然平衡体系的一部分
of the equation, no.
我想说的是
What I mean is that,
过去一百年中 我们积累了
in the last century, we amassed, uh,
划时代的科技力量
landmark technological power,
同时不断有例子证明
and we've consistently proven ourselves incapable
我们无法掌控这种力量
of handling that power.
比如80年前 有谁能预料到核扩散的风险呢
80 years ago, who could have predicted nuclear proliferation?
但这就是发生了
But then there it was.
现在 我们掌控了基因力量
And now we've got genetic power.
这种力量扩散到全球又会花多少时间呢
So, how long is it gonna take for that to spread around the globe,
人们又会用它做什么呢
and what's gonna be done with it?
人类不会止步于再生已经灭绝的恐龙
It aingt gonna stop with the de-extinction of the dinosaurs.
我不太明白你想表达什么
Uh, I'm not sure I know what you're talking about.
我想说的是…
I'm talking about...
人为的 灾难性的
man-made cataclysmic...
改变
change.
什么样的改变
What kind of change?
毁灭性的改变
Change is like death.
只有大难临头 人类才会知道究竟要面对什么
You don't know what it looks like until you're standing at the gates.
事实上 我十分关心恐龙的利益
As a matter of fact, I do have the dinosaurs' best interests in mind.
- 我是一个古生物兽医 - 真的存在这种职业吗
- I'm a paleo-veterinarian. - Is that a real thing?
- 是的 - 你见过古生物吗
- That's a real thing. - You've seen one?
不 我没有亲眼见过
No, I haven't seen one with my own eyes.
不是谁都可以把毕生积蓄花在…
You know, not everyone can afford to spend their life savings...
克莱尔
Claire.
您好…
Oh, uh, hello, hello, um...
- 国会议员德尔加多女士 - 国会议员德尔加多女士
- Congresswoman Delgado. - Congresswoman Delgado.
我叫克莱尔 是这个组织的负责人
I'm-I'm Claire. I'm the lead organizer here.
没问题 但是我能占用你一点时间吗
Uh, of course. But if I could just get a moment of your time?
太好了
Great.
谢谢您
Thank you.
恐龙保护组织的主要工作是
Um, so, our mission here at the Dinosaur Protection Group is to secure
争取联邦资金…
federal funding for a...
刚刚的电话保持了四十秒 你有进步啊
That was, like, 40 seconds. You're getting better.
你别再让你妈妈在帮你买衣服了
You got to stop letting your mom shop for you.
你用不着每次有人惹你生气 就来羞辱我
You don't need to insult me every time someone pisses you off.
兄弟 我是医生
Dude, I'm a doctor,
不是电话推销员
not a telemarketer.
你是干什么的
What is your job again?
接电线的 对吧
You plug in cords, right?
你把我的工作想的太简单了
It's actually more important than it sounds.
- 我能问你一个问题吗 - 请讲
- Can I ask you a question? - Go on.
- 您有孩子吗 - 两个女儿
- Do you have kids? - Two girls.
好的 您的孩子们
Okay. So, your kids,
他们这代人都生活在一个
an entire generation, has grown up in a world
有真实恐龙存活的世界
where dinosaurs are living and breathing.
但很快 他们就只能眼睁睁的看着这些恐龙灭绝
But soon they're gonna have to watch them go extinct...
或者不会
or not,
如果有像您这样的人愿意伸出援手的话
If people like you make a difference.
听证会结束后到我办公室来谈一下
Set up a meeting with my office after the hearing.
太好了
Great.
Yes!
我们现在直播国会…
We now go live to the Capitol...
克莱尔 开始了
Claire. It's on.
- 声音开大点 - 大点声
- Hey, hey, turn it up. - Turn it up.
发言将宣布美国政府是否会采取措施
Take preventative action
保护怒布拉岛上的恐龙
to protect the dinosaurs on Isla Nublar.
经过慎重的讨论 委员会作出决定
After a thorough deliberations, the committee has resolved
不建议立法保护
not to recommend any legislative action
怒布拉岛上的再生灭绝动物
regarding the de-extinct creatures on Isla Nublar.
天命难违
This is an act of God.
当然 我们对这些动物深表同情
And while, of course, we feel great sympathy for these animals,
但我们不能容许政府部门
we cannot condone government involvement
干预这一私有的商业项目
on what amounts to a privately owned venture.
恐龙危在旦夕 却根本没人在乎
They're all gonna die, and no one cares.
我们在乎
We do.
让我一个人静静 大家回去干活吧
Give me one second. Let's get back to work.
好了 大家都别聊天了
Okay, everyone, come on.
喂
Hello?
请问是迪尔林女士吗
May I speak with Ms. Dearing?
- 我是克莱尔·迪尔林 - 早上好
- Yes, this is Claire Dearing. - Good morning.
这里是本杰明·洛克伍德先生的宅邸
I'm calling from Mr. Benjamin Lockwood's estate.
您能稍等一会吗
Would you mind holding for a second?
好的 我会等着
Yes, of c... of course, I'll hold.
(洛克伍德庄园  美国加州北部)
迪尔林女士 您来的真早
Ms. Dearing, you're early.
请进吧
Would you like to step in?
谢谢
Thank you.
我去通知米尔斯先生您来了
I will inform Mr. Mills that you've arrived.
约翰·艾尔弗雷德·哈蒙德
John Alfred Hammond,
侏罗纪公园的创始人
the father of Jurassic Park.
当然我不说你也知道
But of course, you know that.
你好 克莱尔 我是伊莱·米尔斯
Hello, Claire. I'm, uh, I'm Eli Mills.
本·洛克伍德是我的老板
I work for Ben Lockwood.
其实我们七八年前见过一次
We actually met once, seven, eight years ago,
- 你应该不记得了 - 我当然记得
- and you don't remember... - Of course I remember.
你接管他的基金会时…
Haven't you run his foundation since...
还是个大学生 你还记得
Since college, yeah. Y-You remember?
- 当然 - 真厉害
- Yes. - Wow. Cool. He, uh...
他想找个年轻且有理想的人管理他的财产
he wanted someone young and, uh, idealistic to spend his fortune...
当年的我就是这样的
and I used to be both.
跟我来
Follow me.
先跟你讲讲历史
Let me give you a bit of history.
这里是一切开始的地方
This is where it all began.
在那些岛屿 索纳岛 侏罗纪公园所有这些出现之前
Before the island, Sorna, Jurassic Park, all of it.
哈蒙德和洛克伍德在我们脚下的地下室里
Hammond and Lockwood built a custom lab
建立了实验室
in the subbasement,
从琥珀中首次提取了恐龙的DNA
extracted the first DNA from amber right beneath our feet.
我的天啊
Oh, my goodness.
他们在这里所创造的一切就是个奇迹
What they did here was a miracle.
我始终这么认为
I still believe that.
深有同感 克莱尔
So do I, Claire. So do I.
我依然认为人类不该漠视这些动物的命运
And I still believe it matters what happens to those animals.
洛克伍德先生
There is something
想拜托你一件事 克莱尔
Mr. Lockwood would very much like you to do, Claire.
你就当是帮老朋友一个忙
You can call it a favor for an old friend.
我们有一块土地
We have a piece of land.
周围有天然屏障保护
A sanctuary protected by natural barriers,
并且能自给自足的保护区
fully self-sustaining.
恐龙可以在这个新家 安全自由的生活
A new home where the dinosaurs will be secure and free.
你要把它们救出来吗
You're gonna get them out?
拯救它们
You're gonna save them?
不 迪尔林小姐
No, Ms. Dearing.
获得拯救的是我们自己
I'm going to save us.
我们都希望得到点救赎 不是吗
We could both use a touch of redemption, couldn't we?
很高兴又见面了
Lovely to see you again.
我也是 洛克伍德先生
And you, Mr. Lockwood.
这是约翰·哈蒙德的梦想
This was all John Hammond's dream,
让这些动物平静的生活
to let these creatures live in peace.
所以我们建立了这片保护区
So we have created sanctuary.
没有围栏 没有笼子
No fences, no cages,
没有游客
no tourists...
还原大自然母亲的面貌
just as Mother Nature intended.
约翰有句话说的很对
John said it best:
"这些生物不需要我们的保护
"These creatures don't need our protection.
它们需要的是 不受打扰"
They need our absence."
我和约翰年轻的时候都是满腔热血
When we were young, we both shared this passion, John and I.
我们两个当时多幼稚啊
What fools we were.
还没学会走路就想跑
Trying to run before we'd learned to walk.
这应该就是年轻人的通病吧
As all young men do, I suppose.
但我们还是取得了成功
But... we learned.
可惜的是 最终我们分道扬镳
Unfortunately, in the end, it drove us apart.
生活给我们带来的教训有时是非常惨痛的
Life teaches us some very hard lessons,
对吗 克莱尔
doesn't it, Claire?
是的
Yes.
本杰明爵士
Sir Benjamin.
又得吃那些药了
Ah. My bloody medicines.
恕我失陪 克莱尔
Will you excuse me, Claire?
您请便
Of course.
伊莱会告诉你具体事宜
Eli here will help you with the details.
我们会把它们救出来
We will save them.
这可是我们留给…
What a gift...
后代的礼物
for our children.
谢谢您
Thank you.
艾莉丝
Iris.
他有孩子吗 我刚看见了…
Does he have children? I-I thought I saw...
- 一个小女孩 - 他有一个外孙女
- Was there a little girl... - Uh, he has a grandchild.
他女儿出车祸去世了
He's, uh, his daughter died in a car accident.
- 太不幸了 - 是啊
- That's awful. - Yeah, I know.
好在他们祖孙俩感情很好 非常好
But they're very close. Really close.
你们需要我做什么
So what do you need from me?
当时公园里部署了一套追踪系统
There was a tracking system in place at your park...
每只恐龙体内都植入了无线电识别芯片
radio-frequency ID chips in each dinosaur.
- 我记得 - 对 只要我们能进入那套追踪系统
- I remember. - Right. So if we could access that system,
那我们定位和安全捕捉他们的能力
our ability to locate and capture those animals safely
就能大大提升
would increase tenfold.
我们访问那个系统需要你的掌纹
We need your handprint to access the system.
但我真正需要的 克莱尔…
But what I really need, Claire...
是你
is you.
迁移濒危物种严格来说不是合法的
Moving endangered species isn't exactly legal,
但我们这么做是对的
but it's the right thing to do.
没人比你更了解那座公园
No one knows this park as well as you do,
我们需要你的专业能力
and we need that expertise.
- 我们能救出多少物种 - 至少十一个物种
- How many can you save? - 11 species, for sure.
我们也想多救一些 但时间不允许
I mean, more if we can... but time is against us.
其中有一只恐龙
I'm afraid there is one animal in particular
对于我们来说十分棘手
that poses a real challenge for us.
- 布鲁 - 我都不知道她还有名字
- Blue. - I didn't know she had a name,
布鲁很有可能
but Blue is potentially
是地球上智慧水平第二高的生物
the second most intelligent piece of life on this planet,
同时她也是此物种的最后一只了 必须保护好她
and she's the last of her kind. She must be preserved.
她在一英里之外就能闻到你的气味
She can pick up your scent a mile off...
你抓不住她的
you'll never capture her.
这个嘛…
Well...
我们觉得你可能认识一位能帮上忙的人
we thought you might know someone who could help.
也许你能说服他
Maybe you could convince him.
嘿 欧文
Hey, Owen.
欧文
Owen!
天啊
Oh, boy.
嗨
Hi.
又来找事了吗
Back for more, huh?
我请你喝杯酒吧
Can I buy you a beer?
你是把酒带来了 还是我们要去别的地方喝
Did you bring 'em, or do we gotta, like, go somewhere?
抱歉 不是吧
I'm sorry. Seriously?
真不敢相信你居然觉得是你甩了我
I can't believe you think that you left me.
我们来回忆一下当时的对话 好吗
Replay the conversation in your head, all right?
你说 "你想跟流浪汉一样住在货车里吗
You said, "You wanna go live in your van like a bum?
请便吧 欧文"
Go ahead, Owen."
然后我说 "好啊"
And I said, "Okay."
- 这怎么叫你甩了我 - 因为我走了 我离开了你
- So how is that you leaving me? - Because I left. I left you.
是我叫你走 你才走的
You left because I told you to.
结果还是 我走了
And then I left.
因为你不想住在
Because you didn't wanna live in a van
- 路边的货车里 记得吗 - 不不不
- on the side of the road, remember? - No. No, no, no, no.
是因为你不让我开那破车
Because you wouldn't let me drive the damn van
- 五分钟都不行 - 我那叫绅士
- for five minutes. - I'm chivalrous.
- 不然你要我怎么办 - 你这叫顽固
- What can I do? - You are so stubborn.
看看你现在的样子 你在拯救世界呢
Well, look at you now. You're saving the world, so...
至少我在努力
Well, I'm trying at least.
你不能总是遇到问题就逃避 欧文
You can't just run away from everything, Owen.
所以你现在状况如何
So you're what...
是在跟哪个会计约会吗
dating an accountant now?
还是保险精算师
An insurance actuary?
你的皮肤看起来很棒
Your skin looks nice.
- 是皮肤科医生吗 - 欧文
- Dermatologist? - Owen...
- 他会检查你皮肤上的痣吗 - 别说了
- Does he check you for moles? - Stop.
是腹语师吗
Ventriloquist?
我们不是来这讨论这个的 好吗
This is not why we're here, okay?
我知道你来干嘛的
Yeah, I know why we're here.
洛克伍德的小跟班找过我了
Lockwood's little flunky called me.
谈了那个救援行动
Rescue Op.
要把恐龙从快要爆炸的岛上救出来
Save the dinosaurs from an island that's about to explode...
那能出什么岔子呢
what could go wrong?
- 我要去 - 别去
- I'm going. - Don't.
我别无选择
I don't have a choice.
瞎说 你当然有选择
What? Of course you have a choice.
不然呢 我要怎么办 整天造小屋 打台球
So what, I should just... build my own cabin, play pool,
喝喝啤酒 眼睁睁看着那些恐龙全部灭绝吗
and drink beer all day while these dinosaurs go extinct?
对啊
Yeah.
我就喜欢打台球
I like pool.
布鲁还活着
Blue is alive.
天啊 克莱尔
Jesus, Claire.
你亲手养大了她 欧文
You raised her, Owen. You...
你花了那么多年研究她
you spent years of your life working with her.
你舍得看她死在岛上吗
You're just gonna let her die?
舍得啊
Well, yeah.
拜托 你比你自己认为的更善良
Come on, you're a better man than... you think you are.
你应该去写幸运饼干里的小纸条
You should write fortune cookies.
算了 我…
Forget it, I...
包机明天早上出发
There's a charter flight leaving tomorrow morning.
旅客名单上有你
You're on the manifest.
我只是过来告诉你一声
I just wanted to let you know.
好了 进食时间到
All right, chow time, chow time.
退后 退后
Back up. Back off.
悠着点 艾可
Take it easy. Echo.
天哪 东西够吃不用抢
Geez. There's plenty of food.
你们今天是吃糖了吗
God, you guys been eating sugar or something?
一个个都这么活跃
You're hyper today.
好了 好了
Okay, okay.
退后 谢谢 布鲁
Back up. Thank you, Blue.
你拍下来了吗
Did you get that?
放松点 你骑马摔死的几率比坐飞机高多了
Relax. You're more likely to die riding on a horse than in a plane.
不可能 我压根不会去骑马
No, I'm not, because I won't get on a horse.
- 摔死的可能性为零 - 飞机是最安全的交通工具
- My chances are zero. - Planes are the safest way to travel.
这也能叫飞机 我表弟的无人机都比这个大
You call this a plane? My cousin has a drone bigger than this.
欧文
Owen!
富兰克林 你个胆小鬼 快上飞机
Franklin, you wiener, get on the plane.
我还以为你不会来了呢
Didn't think you were gonna ever show up.
这位是齐娅·罗德里格兹
Oh, um, this is Zia Rodriguez.
- 齐娅 - 嘿 你好吗
- Zia. - Hey. How you doing?
- 很好 你呢 - 我很好
- Yeah. Real good. How are you? - Good.
这位是富兰克林·韦伯 系统分析员
Franklin Webb. Systems analyst.
你害怕坐飞机吗
Nervous flyer?
给你一匹九百多斤重
Would you ride
常年遭到虐待的马 你敢骑吗
a thousand-pound horse that's been abused all its life?
我曾经着骑摩托 跟一群迅猛龙穿越丛林
I rode my motorcycle through the jungle with a pack of raptors.
我跟你八字不合
We're not compatible.
梅茜
Maisie?
你总是躲躲藏藏
You're always hiding from me.
我的工作可不是天天找你
This is not my job, looking for you.
梅茜
Maisie!
Maisie?
快出来
Come out!
臭丫头
Oh! You silly sausage.
你要吓死我啊
You'll be the death of me.
哪天我真的被你吓死了
You know, one day my heart might really stop.
你要怎么办
Then what would you do?
去森林里跟狮子一起住吗
Go and live in the forest with the lions?
森林里没有狮子
There are no lions in the forest.
你外公找你好久了
Your grandfather's been asking for you.
- 真的吗 - 快去找你外公
- Really? - Mm-hmm. So you go see your grandfather,
- 然后马上去洗澡 - 我不想洗澡
- and then you go straight to your bath. - I don't want a bath.
你说什么 姑娘 要注意发音
A what? Queen's English, girl. "Bath"!
- 洗澡 - 洗澡
- Bath. Bath. - Bath.
是洗澡 不是"洗找"你可不是野兽
Bath, not "bath." You're not a wild animal.
别闹了
Stop it.
- 嗨 外公 - 你来了
- Hi, Grandpa. - Ah, there you are.
过来 陪我坐会
Come over and sit by me.
- 我想你了 - 我去游猎了
- I've missed you. - I was on safari all the way
一天之内我从白垩纪游历到了侏罗纪
through the Cretaceous to the Jurassic in one day.
- 厉害 你都看到了什么 - 大部分都是食草动物
- Oh, my. What'd you see? - Mostly herbivores.
不过我见到了一只霸王龙
There was one T. rex, though.
场面一度很血腥
Casualties, of course.
艾莉丝也遭殃了
Iris included.
她都吓得魂飞魄散了
She jumped out of her skin.
你跟你妈妈一样古灵精怪
You have your mother's wicked sense of humor.
我长得像她吗
Do I look like her?
当然
Oh, yes.
你简直就是她的翻版
You could be her mirror image.
妈妈去过那座公园吗
Did my mother ever visit the park?
去过一次
Once...
很多年前了
a long time ago.
如果她在的话 也一定会去救它们的
She would have saved them, too, you know.
她会把它们全部都救出来
She would have saved them all.
(侏罗纪世界)
克莱尔
Claire.
我是肯·惠特利 欢迎回来
Ken Wheatley. Welcome back.
没想到救援行动规模这么大
Quite an operation you've got going on here.
洛克伍德先生十分重视此次人道主义行动
Mr. Lockwood takes his humanitarian efforts very seriously.
那个"迅猛龙牛仔"在哪
Where's the, uh, raptor wrangler?
是动物行为专家
Animal behaviorist.
- 欧文·格瑞帝 - 欧文 我是肯·惠特利
- Owen Grady. - Hey, Owen. Ken Wheatley.
你是传说中的"白人猎手"吗
And you are... Great White Hunter?
算是吧
I guess.
我是探险指导专家
I'm the expedition facilitator.
天啊 热死了
Oh, God! It's hot!
很快会热的更夸张
It's about to get a whole lot hotter.
继续走 可以通过
Keep it moving! You're all clear!
继续走 你们可以通过
Go! Go, you've got the green light!
这边 我们走
This way, let's go!
继续走 往前开
Let's go! Keep it moving!
停一停 等一下
Hold it! Hold up!
驱蚊喷雾要吗
Need some bug spray?
你要吗
Bug spray?
霸王龙已经死了 对吧
The T. rex would be dead by now, right?
不一定 如果生存环境彻底改变
No. It's impossible to know the max lifespan of a clone
我们就无法估算克隆生物的寿命
in a completely different environment.
比如洞穴人只能活二十年
Take a caveman that would have lived 20 years,
给他吃好的 给他看医生
feed him prime meals, give him health care,
他的寿命就能翻五倍
he's gonna live... five times as long.
所以霸王龙已经死了
So she'd be dead by now.
对吗
Right?
想起不好的往事了吗
Bad memories?
也有美好的
Some were good.
那是什么
What was that?
是霸王龙吗
Is it the T. rex?
我们得近点看
I have to see this.
嘿 小姐
Hey. Miss?
小姐
Miss!
那片区域不安全
This area's not secured.
看看
Look at that.
想不到我居然能亲眼看到恐龙
Never thought I'd see one in real life.
她真漂亮
She's beautiful.
可以走了吗
Can we...
好了 下车吧
Okay, let's go.
好了 好了
Okay, okay.
找到主系统
Okay, main system.
启动控制
Turn on control.
应该能行的
It should be working.
快点 猛男
Come on, tiger.
你到底行不行
You know what you're doing?
你先请 猛男
After you, tiger.
我们能确定这些生物芯片还有信号吗
Are we sure these biometric chips are still transmitting?
普通电池应该早没电了
Battery would be dead by now.
- 好吧 - 恐龙自身就是电源
- All right. - The dinosaur is the battery.
体温和运动会转化为电能
They're powered by body heat and movement.
手
Hand.
需要多久才能…
How much longer until...
进去了
I'm in.
有大量信号聚集在东部码头
There's a large concentration on the east dock.
那是我们的船 我们已经抓到了一大批
That's our boat... we've already captured a bunch of 'em.
不需要靠追踪系统吗
Without the tracking system?
大型食草动物很好找
The big herbivores are easy to find.
能单独显示那只迅猛龙吗
Can you isolate that raptor?
- 我需要物种代码 - D-9
- I need a species code. - D-nine.
(确定D9所在位置)
她在那 我要借用一下你的卡车
There she is. I'm gonna need to borrow your truck.
我跟你一块去
I'm coming with you...
说不定她会需要接受治疗
we don't know what kind of condition she might be in.
小姐 外面可不安全
Miss, things could get hairy out there.
这种镇静剂的药性很强
These are powerful sedatives.
用量过大可能会造成呼吸衰竭
One too many, and she could have respiratory failure.
而且 我没你想的那么柔弱无知
Also, I'm not as soft and witless as your comment implies.
出发吧 大块头
Let's go, beefcake.
欧文
Oh, Owen?
小心点 好吗
Be careful, okay?
如果我没能活着回来
If I don't make it back...
要记住…
remember...
是你叫我来的
you're the one who made me come.
我不会有事的
I'll be all right.
我们开着车是没法靠近她的
We're not gonna get any closer to her in this thing.
- 在这停车 - 停车
- We should stop here. - Hold up!
保持警惕 注意安全
Load out, look alive, stay alive.
- 我们会保护你的 - 好
- We got your back, brother. - Yeah.
克莱尔 我得一个人去看看
Claire, I'm gonna have to track her alone.
我要你帮我留意她的动向 明白吗
I'll need you to be my eyes if she runs. Copy?
明白
Copy that.
惠特利 我找到了新鲜的痕迹
Wheatley, I'm on fresh sign.
等我的信号
Wait for my signal.
找到你了
There you are.
嘿 小妞 你想我吗
Hey, girl. You miss me?
冷静 嘿
Easy. Hey!
嘿
Hey.
我给你带了好东西
I brought you something.
给你
Here you go.
就是这样
That's right.
好吧
Okay.
你认识我
You know me.
看着我
Eyes on me.
对了
Yeah.
这就对了
对了
Yeah.
你认识我
You know me.
对了
That's right.
这就对了
别开枪…
Hold your...
我叫你们等我信号
I told you to wait for my signal!
叫你的人立刻后退
Back your men up right now.
不 等等 别向她开枪
No, hey, no, no, don't shoot her!
惠利特 你这个混蛋
Wheatley, you son of a bitch!
欧文 你们这是干什么
Owen! What are you doing?!
欧文
Owen.
我要是死了
You shoot me...
那只恐龙也活不了
and that animal dies.
你现在没有条件威胁我们 亲爱的
I think we have the drop on you, sweetheart.
她在流血 如果我不对她进行急救…
She's losing blood, and if I don't treat her...
她绝不可能活着回到营地
she'll never make it back to camp.
这样吧
How about this?
那东西要是死了 我就杀了你
That animal dies, I shoot you.
你负责治好她
You're gonna take care of her.
我们撤
Let's move out!
切断线路 我们走
Cut the cord and let's go!
我们离开这里
Let's get out of here!
不 不
No! No! No!
不 等等
No, wait!
他们是在保护我们吗 发生什么了
Wait, a-are they protecting us? What's going on?
(锁定)
(错误)
恐怕不是
I don't think so.
我为什么要来
Why am I here?!
米尔斯 我们抓到她了
Hey, Mills, we got her done!
任务完成
Mission accomplished!
真是生死攸关
Just in the nick of time.
惠利特 你在搞什么
Wheatley, what the hell is going on there?
我们比原计划晚了一天
We're a day behind schedule already.
在我回来之前
I want that money in the bank
- 把钱打进我的账户 好吗 - 好
- by the time I get back, all right? - Okay, good.
听好了 不得再拖延了
Listen to me, no more delays, okay?
- 米尔斯先生 - 如果我们没抓到那些动物…
- Mr. Mills? - If we don't get those animal...
我现在没空 梅茜 听话 如果我们…
Not now, Maisie, thank you. If we don't get those...
- 米尔斯先生 恐龙得救了吗 - 我说了我现在没空
- Mr. Mills, are the dinosaurs safe... - I said not now!
米尔斯 米尔斯
Mills?! Mills?!
对不起 亲爱的 我在打一个重要电话
I'm sorry, honey. This is an important call.
你先去图书馆
If you go up to the library,
- 我过会就去找你 - 好的
- I'll meet you up there in a few minutes. - Okay.
好吗 我保证等会全都讲给你听
Okay, I'll tell you all about it, I promise.
- 好的 - 好
- Okay. - Okay. Okay.
惠特利
Wheatley...
马上给我把那些恐龙运回来
you get those animals here now.
我还想要笔奖金 我们抓到了那只布鲁
I want that bonus. We got the blue one.
先把她送回来见我
Bring her to me first!
好的
All right.
不
No.
喂 有谁能听到我吗
Hello? Can anyone hear me?
有人吗
Hello?
喂 有人听的到吗
Hello? Is anybody there?
有人能听到吗
Can anybody copy?
我试了各种方法都打不开
I'm-I'm trying everything.
卡住了
It's jammed.
接受这份工作吧 儿子 能提高交际能力
"Just take the job, son, build your people skills."
是的 谢了 爸爸
Yeah, thanks, Dad.
打开了
That's it.
危险警报
Proximity alert.
有什么东西朝这来了
Something's coming.
这条隧道通向哪
Where does that tunnel lead?
通向公园其他的…
Well, it connects to the rest of the...
区域
park.
是霸王龙 是霸王龙
It's the T. rex. It's the T. rex.
是霸王龙 克莱尔 是霸王龙
It's the T. rex. Claire, it's the T. rex.
是霸王龙 霸王龙来了
It's the T. rex. It's the T. rex.
别吵了 不是霸王龙
Will you stop? It's not the T. rex.
应该不是
Probably.
"Probably"?
熔岩 熔岩
Lava! Lava!
熔岩
Lava. Lava.
深呼吸 富兰克林
Deep breaths, Franklin.
看见没 不是霸王龙
See?! Not a T. rex!
有什么区别吗
How is this better?!
克莱尔 我们该怎么办
Claire, what do we do?! What do we do?!
卡住了
It's stuck!
椅子
Chair!
快点 我们走
Come on! Let's go!
快点 富兰克林
Come on, Franklin!
我们得救了 太好了
We made it! Yeah!
快点 快点 快点
Come on, come on, come on, come on, come on!
快点 快点
Come on, come on, come on!
对 快走 快走
Yes, yes, go, go! Go, go!
克莱尔
Claire.
天啊…
Holy sh...
快跑
Run!
进去
Go, go!
- 好了 - 好了
- Okay, okay. - Okay.
系好安全带 富兰克林
Buckle up, Franklin.
快进来
Get in!
欧文
Owen!
我们得想办法出去
We got to get out.
我们刚从悬崖上摔下来
We just fell from the cliff.
我们没死 我们还活着
We're alive. We're alive.
弗兰克 快点
Franklin, move.
不 不好了
No. No, no, no!
不 克莱尔 这东西进水了 我们要沉下去了
No. Claire, we're gonna sink! Water's leaking!
天啊
Oh. Oh, God!
我们得赶紧出去
We need to get out!
富兰克林 小心
Franklin, watch out!
我想回家
I want to go home!
欧文
Owen!
- 欧文 - 欧文
- Owen! - Owen?
欧文
Owen.
好的
Okay.
闪开 靠边
Move! Move!
不 不要…
No! No, no, no, no, no, no, no, no.
推
Push!
欧文 不
Owen! No, no.
他要去哪
Where's he going?
好吧 冷静 别慌
Okay. Okay, don't panic.
空气不够了
We're running out of air.
- 我们死定了 - 没事的 没事的
- We're not gonna make it. - We are. We are.
深吸一口气
Take a deep breath.
- 齐娅呢 - 我们被骗了
- Where is Zia? - It was a double-cross.
她被带走了 她和布鲁一起被带了
They took her. She must be with Blue.
你现在还能追踪他们吗
Hey, can you still track 'em?
不行了
Not anymore.
都是骗人的
It was a lie. It was a lie.
混蛋 全是骗子
Bastards! It was all a lie!
也不全是
Not all of it.
快点 快 快
Move it! Move! Move!
值钱的东西 全都给我装上船
Anything of value, I want on that boat!
- 你那边怎么样了 - 螺栓没法固定
- How you doing?! - The bolt won't give!
那就捆好了 整个搬走 动作快
Well, just button it up, and we'll tow it on! Let's go!
快点
Come on, now.
嘿…
Hey! Hey, hey, hey!
等一下 等一下
Hang on! Wait up!
让这辆车停下 停车
Stop that truck! Stop it!
嘿 亲爱的 你好啊
Hey, sweetheart. Hello, hello.
真不错
Beautiful.
等你清醒了之后 才会知道疼
You're gonna feel that when you wake up.
嘿 把枪放下
Hey, put your weapon down!
别用枪管指着她的头
You got the barrel pointed right at her head!
嘿 惠特利
Hey, Wheatley!
齐娅在他们手上 他们在撤离
They have Zia. They're loading out.
他们都抓到恐龙了 还叫我们来干嘛
If they already had the dinosaurs, why do they need us?
他们需要借助追踪系统抓布鲁
They needed the tracking system to capture Blue.
她在那 看样子不太好
There she is. She don't look good.
我们得上那条船
We need to get on that boat.
我觉得我们在岩石后面挺安全的
The rock's good. We're safe on the rock.
船还是岩浆 你选一个 富兰克林
It's the boat or the lava, Franklin.
好吧 船不错 我选船
All right, boat's good. I'm all about the boat.
动作快 上船
Go, go, get on the boat!
上船 动作快点
Get on the boat now! Go, go!
快点 跑起来
Move it, move it!
去卡车那里
Get that truck!
富兰克林
Franklin!
- 快去把车子发动起来 - 好的
- Hey, get that truck going! - Okay.
- 没事吧 - 我死了吗
- You okay? - Am I dead?
还没有 小子
Not yet, kid.
快点
Come on!
快来把手给我 加油
Give me your hand! Reach!
加油
Come on, reach!
抓紧了
Hold on!
(世外桃源号)
(警报  检测到火山活动)
米尔斯先生
Mr. Mills?
有位客户在等您
Your visitor's waiting.
艾威索先生
Mr. Eversoll.
终于有幸见到你本人了
It's a pleasure to meet you in person after all this time.
- 你好吗 - 请问一下
- How are ya? - Excuse me.
- 是 - 恐龙在哪里
- Yeah. - Where are the dinosaurs?
恐龙在路上
The dinosaurs are, uh, are en route.
你准备让我拿这些标本去拍卖吗
Oh, so am I supposed to sell these ones?
这一点你不用担心
Look, you don't need to worry, okay?
它们很快就到
They will be here soon.
我不喜欢跟外行人做生意
I-I don't really work with amateurs,
所以我会通知买家 取消这次会面
so I'm gonna contact my buyers and call this off.
它们明天就到
They will be here tomorrow,
我不会让你的买家失望的
and your buyers won't be disappointed.
相信我 不管他们想用于
Trust me, whatever their interest...
农业 工业还是狩猎
agricultural, industrial, sport hunting...
我们都能满足他们
we will have something to suit them.
十一种恐龙 每种都有独一无二的生物医药价值
11 species, each with unique biopharmaceutical properties.
我预估每种可值四百万
I estimate four million per species.
四百万对于我们这行的人来说只是小钱
Four million is a slow Tuesday where I'm from.
我在浪费我的时间
You're wasting my time.
一亿对你来说也是小钱吗
You ever made a hundred million on a Tuesday?
这些都是陈年旧事
All this is in the past.
我想跟你谈的是未来
I want to talk to you about the future.
我给你十分钟时间
I'll give you ten minutes.
拍卖怒布拉岛上的恐龙主要是为了
The whole point of selling the Isla Nublar dinosaurs
给这里研发未来的业务筹集资金
is to finance our future operations here.
这是种子基金
It's, uh, seed money.
这只是试水 后面还有更有野心的目标
Call it a-an overture to something much more ambitious.
是啊 我猜还有更大的利润
Yeah, and more lucrative, I guess.
没错 我们启用了原有的设施
Right. We've reactivated the old facilities,
对技术进行了升级
updated the technology,
并招募了一批全球顶尖的遗传学专家
and imported the best geneticists from around the world.
这个项目已经筹备多年
This operation has been many years in the planning.
基因是一片尚待开发的新领域
Genetic power is an uncharted frontier.
它的发展潜力远远超乎你的想象
The potential for growth is more than you can fathom.
这边请
This way, please.
如果说这段令人唏嘘的历史
If the entire run of our sorry history
使我们明白了一个亘古不变的事实
has taught us one irrevocable lesson,
那就是战争对人类而言无法避免
it's that man is inevitably drawn to war
人们愿意用尽一切手段 只为赢得胜利
and is willing to use any means necessary to win it.
你打算把它们变成武器吗
You're gonna weaponize them?
人类利用动物打仗已有数百年历史
We've been using animals in combat for centuries.
马 大象
Horses, elephants.
苏联人在斯大林格勒
The Soviets used disease-bearing rats
- 利用老鼠携带的病毒对付德国人 - 没错
- against the Germans at Stalingrad. - Yes, yes.
我们的遗传学家 已经创造出了
Our geneticists have created
亨利·吴的杰作的直系后代
a direct descendant of Henry Wu's masterpiece,
也就是那只摧毁侏罗纪世界的野兽
the animal that took down Jurassic World.
暴虐霸王龙
Indominus rex.
在火山爆发之前
Her DNA, retrieved from the island
我们就从岛上取得了她的DNA
way before its destruction, forms the architecture
为此创造出了一个新的生物
of a completely new creature.
每块骨骼和肌肉都是为了狩猎和杀戮而设计的
Every bone and muscle designed for hunting and killing.
多亏了欧文·格雷迪的研究
And thanks to Owen Grady's research,
她会完全服从人类的指令
it follows human command.
我们叫它
We call it...
暴虐迅猛龙
the Indoraptor.
外公
Grandpa?
Grandpa.
梅茜 你怎么还没睡
Maisie? What are you doing up?
今天有个男人来找米尔斯先生
There was a man here today with Mr. Mills.
可能是来找他谈保护区的事
It was probably just some business about the sanctuary,
- 这没什么 - 我听到他们说
- that's all. - I heard them talking...
他们要把恐龙卖掉
they're going to sell the dinosaurs.
然后把它们运到这里
They're bringing them here.
你肯定是听错了
I'm sure you misunderstood.
- 我绝对没有听错 - 梅茜
- I know what I heard, Grandpa. - Maisie,
已经很晚了 你该睡了
it's way past your bedtime.
这件事我们明天早上再说
Let's talk about this in the morning.
- 可是… - 梅茜
- But... - Maisie,
我明天会查清楚的
I'll find out tomorrow.
快去睡觉
Go to bed.
晚安
Good night.
晚安 宝贝儿
Good night, my heart.
天啊
Oh! Jesus.
没事的 再坚持一会
It's okay, Blue. Just a little longer.
天啊 你们还活着…
Oh, my God! You guys are alive! You...
他们居然把她伤成这样
Oh, look what they've done to her.
- 这群混蛋是什么人 - 动物走私犯
- Who are these assholes? - Animal traffickers.
看他们是怎么对这些恐龙的 他们才不会送它们去保护区
Look how they're treating them. They're not gonna take 'em to a sanctuary,
他们要卖掉它们
they're gonna sell them.
除了布鲁 他们要她还有别的用处
Not Blue. They need her for something else.
什么用处
Like what?
我不知道 但她…
I don't know, but she's...
她在流血
she's hemorrhaging,
而我没有医疗工具维持她的生命体征
and I don't have instruments, and they want to keep her alive.
没事的 没事的
You're all right. You're all right.
克莱尔 过来
Claire, come here.
用手按住这
Come on. Put your hand here.
用力按住
Steady pressure.
嘿 嘿…
Hey, hey, hey. Hey.
小心点
Watch out.
我需要同样动物的血样来给她输血
I can't take the bullet out
不然我没法取出子弹
without a transfusion from another animal.
你们谁知道怎么找静脉
Which one of you knows how to find a vein?
我在红十字会当过志愿者
Oh. I-I did a blood drive for the Red Cross.
太好了
Great.
富兰克林 你过来代替克莱尔
Okay. Franklin, take over for Claire.
我不行 不行 不行…
No, no, no, no, no, no...
富兰克林 快点
Franklin. Now.
用力按住
Steady pressure.
我的天啊 天啊
Oh, my God. Oh, my God.
我嘴里有吗 溅到我嘴里了吗
Is it in my mouth? Did it get in my mouth?
- 确定？- 你没事
- You sure? - You're good.
所有动物应该都打了镇静剂
All of the animals should be sedated.
找到坚尾龙类恐龙
Look for any kind of tetanuran.
它们的血型应该跟布鲁相似
Their blood type should be close enough.
要找有两个或三个脚趾的食肉类恐龙
Look for carnivores with two or three fingers.
不要超过三根脚趾的
No more than three.
我想船上应该就有一只
I think there's one on board.
开什么玩笑呢
You got to be kidding me.
镇静剂药效还在
She's tranqued.
行了
Okay, okay.
我准备好了 来吧
Okay, I got it. Come on.
好的
Okay.
你没事吧
Are you okay?
我没事
I'm okay.
快来
Come on.
你来抽血
You're gonna have to do it.
我不行 她的皮太厚了
I can't, I... the skin is too thick.
我得用两只手才能给静脉施压
I have to use both my hands to put pressure on the vein.
你来抽血
You got to do it.
不行 我够不到
I-I can't. I can't reach.
你爬到背上来
You're gonna have to climb up there.
我才不…
Oh, I'm not...
我是不会爬到她背上的
No, no. I'm not gonna climb up there.
没事的 跟骑牛没什么两样
You'll be okay. It's like riding a bull.
骑牛 你当我跟你一样
"Riding a bull"? I didn't grow up in a rodeo
- 是在竞技场混的吗 - 她现在没醒
- or wherever you came from. - She's asleep now.
不代表她待会不会醒
I can't say that she's gonna be asleep a minute from now,
赶紧的
so get up.
好吧
Okay, fine.
天啊 她可真臭
Oh, my God, she stinks.
我的天
Jesus.
慢点 慢点
Gently. Gently!
干得漂亮
Good job.
这画面毫无违和感
You're making this look totally normal.
你得用力才能扎进去
You're gonna have to jam it in there.
她的皮很厚
It's really thick skin.
- 准备好了吗 - 好了
- Ready? - Yeah.
- 好的 一 - 一
- Okay. One... - One...
- 二 - 二
- Two... - Two...
扎
Stab!
- 该死 - 欧文
- Oh, shoot. - Owen!
成功了
It's working.
门没关上
That door is open.
我来关
I got it.
栅栏
The bars!
栅栏 欧文
The bars, Owen. Owen,
我能从上面出去 快点
I can get through there. Come on.
快跳 欧文
Jump, Owen!
欧文 跳
Owen, jump.
快
Now!
瞧见我敏捷的身手了吗
Did you see that?
血袋你没忘记拿吧
Please tell me you got the blood.
(限制入内)
这是德尔塔
This is Delta.
她是四只兽脚恐龙之一
She's one of the holdover theropods,
第二组的幸存者之一
one of the survivors from the second group.
现在注意看
Now, watch this.
只要我表现出弱小的样子
I show any sign of weakness whatsoever...
看见没
See that?
176天 布鲁表现出
Day 176. Blue is showing
前所未有的高度顺从
unprecedented levels of compliance.
现在跟我在一起的就是布鲁
Here I am with Blue.
她是新一组中的脚类恐龙
She's a theropod from the new group.
我表现出弱小的样子…
I show signs of weakness...
嘿
Hey.
我没事
I'm okay.
她…
She...
非常与众不同
she's pretty extraordinary.
布鲁 表现出了
Blue, displaying levels
对外界事物的关心和兴趣
of interest, concern,
具备超高智能和认知性情感联系
hyper-intelligence, uh, cognitive bonding.
看到了吗
See that?
她歪着脑袋
She's tilting her head.
探着身子
She's craning forward. Sh...
眼睛不停在转 她很好奇
Increased eye movement... she's curious.
她有共情
She's showing empathy.
我要在她腿上切个口子
Okay, I'm gonna make an incision
取出子弹
in her leg to remove the bullet.
这腿部肌肉组织真厚
It's a lot of muscle tissue.
她会好起来的
She's gonna be okay.
布鲁才是关键
Blue is the key.
你真棒
Bless you.
只要有了布鲁 你就可以指挥这些迅猛龙做任何事
You have Blue, you get these raptors to do anything.
你确定她会活下来吗
You're sure she'll live?
如果真的死掉了 我们还有血液样本
If it dies, we have blood samples.
不 那还不够好
No, no, no. That's not good enough.
那只迅猛龙是行为样本
The raptor is a behavioral specimen.
我们需要她健健康康的
We need her in good health.
又不是我朝它开枪的
I didn't shoot the damn thing.
你能指望我做什么
What do you want me to do, huh?
你压根没明白
You don't have the faintest comprehension
我在这里研究什么
of what I'm doing here.
你明白创造一种全新的生命形式有多复杂吗
Do you understand the complexity of creating an entirely new life-form?
不 但我知道
Uh, no, but I understand
为它付账有多复杂
the complexity of paying for it, okay?!
如果布鲁没能活着到这来
All your money will have been wasted
你的钱都付之东流了
if I don't get Blue here in good health.
为了更好掌控新一代恐龙
To get the next iteration under control,
需要让它与一个遗传基因相近的个体
it needs to form a familial bond
建立家庭纽带关系
with a closely-related genetic link.
- 说人话 亨利 - 它需要母亲
- English, Henry. - It needs a mother!
布鲁的DNA将构成暴虐迅猛龙基因的一部分
Blue's DNA will be part of the next Indoraptor's makeup.
基因代码决定了
So it will be genetically coded
它会服从她的权威 体现她的特征
to recognize her authority and assume her traits.
共情 顺从
Empathy, obedience...
这些在你现在的原型身上都没有
everything the prototype you have now is missing.
好吧 需要多久才能完成
Okay, so how long is this gonna take?
这不是短跑 米尔斯先生
It's not a sprint, Mr. Mills.
这是马拉松
It's a marathon.
马拉松听起来很贵
A marathon sounds expensive.
我没那个时间也没那个耐性了 亨利
Besides, time is running out and so is my patience, Henry.
你要明白
You have to understand,
这是尚未开发的全新领域
this is all uncharted territory.
从遗传角度上说
A wolf, genetically,
狼和斗牛犬几乎没有区别
is barely distinguishable from a bulldog,
但现在那些灰色界域里
but within that gray area...
蕴藏着心灵
is art.
我不想听你作诗 亨利
Spare me the poetry, Henry.
你能做到吗 你能不能做到
Can you do it? Can you do it?
是的 我能做到
Yes, I can do it.
那就去做吧
Well, then do it.
谢谢
Thank you.
天啊 你真是个烦人的混蛋
God, you're a pain in the ass.
嘿
Hey! Hey!
梅茜
Maisie!
那是什么东西
What is that?
What is it?!
把门锁上 别让她从房间里出来
Keep her in there and keep the door locked.
你要把她关起来吗
You want to keep her locked in?
我就是这个意思
That's exactly what I want.
本杰明先生要你现在就去见他
Sir Benjamin needs to see you now.
我相信应该是很重要的事情
I believe it's important.
排好队
Put it on line!
所有船员 准备停靠卸货
All crew prepare for docking.
打起精神来 各位
Look alive, soldiers!
- 所有船员 准备停靠卸货 - 我们走
- All crew prepare for docking. - Let's go, let's go!
动起来 伙计们
Let's move it, boys.
我们到了
We're here.
到哪儿了
Where?
上车 我们走
Get in your truck and let's go.
- 快点 快点 - 躲好 躲好
- Move, move. - Move, move, move.
还有心跳吗
You got a heartbeat?
有啊 你呢
Yeah. Do you?
我们需要血液样本
I need blood samples.
我不是来帮你们重置食物链的
I'm not here to help you reset the food chain, so...
要血样就抽自己的去吧
take your own damn samples.
这女人太彪悍了
What a nasty woman.
快走 快走
Go, go, now, now. Go.
所有船员注意 所有船员注意
Attention, all crew. Attention, all crew.
驾驶员们快上车
Drivers, get to your vehicles.
嘿
Hey!
你在这干什么
What the hell's going on?
我在…
I was, um...
我刚才需要人搭把手
I need an extra pair of hands.
- 他主动来帮忙的 - 你是船员吗
- He volunteered. - You deck crew?
- 对 - 要卸货了 跟我来
- Aye, aye. - We're loading out. Follow me.
意思是我们现在要下船了吗
Uh, does that mean we're leaving the ship right now?
就是这个意思
That is what "loading out" means.
别傻站着了 快跟我走
Now get moving. Come on, follow me.
快点 孩子
Come on, kid.
- 该死 - 还有很多事要做
- Shit. - There's lots to do.
- 快点 快点 - 糟了
- Get a move on, come on. - Oh, no.
他会被识破的
He's not gonna make it.
- 快点 快点 - 我们得帮帮他
- Move it! Come on, move! - We have to help him.
你待在这儿 我去救他
Stay here. I'll get him.
来不及了 我们走
There's no time. Let's go.
可以了
Good to go!
走吧
Roll out.
他们要把恐龙运去哪儿
Where are they taking them?
很快就知道了
We're about to find out.
我们走
Let's go!
撑住 姑娘
Come on, girl.
太好了
Yes!
这里是洛克庄园
This is Lockwood's estate.
他的车库肯定很大
He must have one big-ass garage.
快点 十分钟内完成卸货
Come on! We want this offloaded in ten mikes.
电他
Hit him!
你以为自己能瞒天过海吗
Did you really think you could get away with it?
在我的眼皮底下
In my own house.
是你托付我
You entrusted me
要带着你的财富走向未来
to guide your fortune into the future.
我做到了
I have done that.
混账
Damn you!
去拿电话
Pick up that phone.
我要你向警方自首
I want you to call the police.
你最好还是自己坦白吧
It'll be easier if the story comes from you.
如你所愿 爵士
As you say, sir.
我一直在想 约翰·哈蒙德是对的
You know, I've been thinking, John Hammond was right.
你的所作所为确实有违天理
It was an unholy thing that you did.
这儿有罪的人不止我一个 你说呢 爵士
I'm not the only guilty one here, am I, sir?
嘿
Hey.
我们去镇上通知执法部门来阻止他们
We hit that town, we call the cavalry, shut this down.
你们好
Hello.
你们应该乖乖留在岛上的
You should have stayed on the island.
那样也许还能活
Better odds.
嗨 克莱尔
Hi, Claire.
我过来就想跟你道个歉
I just wanted to come and apologize.
我本来没想把你卷进来
I didn't want to bring you into any of this,
但为了抓到那只迅猛龙只能这么做
but it was the only way that we could get the raptor.
我们需要它
We needed it.
算了
Come on.
所以呢
So, what?
这就是你的目的吗
This is it?
像你这么聪明的人
I mean, you're a smart guy.
完全可以建个基金会
You could have started a foundation,
专注于治愈癌症 而不是… 这个
cured cancer, but instead you... what?
贩卖濒危物种
Sell endangered species?
我救了这些动物
I saved these animals.
你为了钱背叛了一个垂暮之人
You betrayed a dying man for money.
克莱尔 我欣赏你的理想主义
Claire, I admire your idealism,
但我们都利用过这些动物
but we both exploited these animals.
至少 我敢作敢当
At least I have the integrity to admit it.
我从没做过任何违法的事情
I never, ever did anything remotely illegal.
是你批准了暴虐霸王龙的研发
You authorized the creation of the Indominus rex.
为了赚钱 你把一个活生生的动物关在笼子里
You exploited a living thing in a cage for money.
跟我有什么区别
How is that different? Huh?
还有你
And you.
你证明了迅猛龙能够服从命令
The man who proved raptors can follow orders.
你就从来没想过把它们应用于实践吗 欧文
You never thought about the applications of your research, Owen?
没想过一只训练有素的迅猛龙能卖几百万吗
How many millions a trained predator might be worth?
你们俩 是这个新世界的缔造者
You two, you're the parents of the new world.
嘿
Hey!
- 放开他 - 欧文
- Let him go. - Owen.
我要拧下他的手
I think I'll break it.
放开他
Let him go.
克莱尔 我只想…
Claire, I just want... aah!
这两个人怎么处置
Say, how we gonna end this?
反正对其他人来说
Well, as far as everybody else is concerned,
他们已经在岛上化成灰了
they burned up on the island.
买家们陆续到了
Buyers on approach.
今晚门庭若市
Looks like a full house.
收到
Roger that.
晚上好
Good evening.
晚上好 晚上好
Good evening. Good evening.
- 欢迎光临 先生们 - 晚上好
- Welcome, gentlemen. Welcome. - Good evening.
他是里奇·拉斯洛
Ah, and these guys are development rep
阿尔达瑞斯制药公司的开发代表
for Aldaris Pharmaceuticals.
- 很好 - 留胡子的是
- Great. - And the guy in the beard
格雷戈·阿德里奇的代理
is a proxy for Gregor Adlrich,
那个斯洛文尼亚军火商
the Slovenian arms dealer.
那位是兰德·马格努斯的代理人
Uh, equine buyers for Rand Magnus,
他是来自休斯顿的石油大亨
an oil magnate from Houston.
他们对什么恐龙感兴趣
Well, what-what's their interest?
他们的口味很独特
Strictly personal.
他的孩子想要一只三角龙宝宝
His kid wants a baby triceratops.
格伦 詹妮特近来可好
Glenn, how's Janet?
她挺好的 谢谢
She's doing fine, thanks.
直走就行 格伦
Straight ahead, Glenn.
他们只想买两只食肉动物
Well, he only wants carnivores. Two of them.
洛克伍德先生今晚可以大赚一笔了
Looks like Lockwood's gonna have a very good night.
他会出席拍卖会吗
Will he be joining us?
不太可能
Um, that's very unlikely.
外公
Grandpa?
Grandpa.
外公 醒醒
Grandpa, wake up.
外公
Grandpa?
外公 醒醒 快醒醒
Grandpa, wake up. Wake up.
艾莉丝
Iris!
没救了
It's over.
太不幸了
What a tragedy.
既然他已经不在了
I suppose now he's gone,
你也该另谋高就了
you'll be looking for another situation.
不
No.
梅茜需要我
Maisie needs me.
现在我是她的监护人
I'm her guardian now.
她需要什么就不劳你操心了
What she needs is no longer your concern.
您不像我这么了解她
You don't understand her the way I do.
我了解她的价值
I understand her value.
但她是我养大的
But I raised her.
我养大了…
I raised...
她们俩
both of them.
- 求您 米尔斯先生 - 再见 艾莉丝
- Please, Mr. Mills... - Good-bye, Iris.
你还记得第一次
Do you remember the first time
见到恐龙的时候吗
you saw a dinosaur?
第一次看到它们时 感觉就像…
First time you see them, it's like...
见到了奇迹
a miracle.
你在书上看到过它们 在博物馆见过它们的骸骨
You read about them in books, you see the bones in museums,
但你心里并不完全相信
but you don't really believe it.
它们就像个神话
They're like myths.
直到有天你看到了…
And then you see...
第一只活着的恐龙
the first one alive.
这不是你的错
This is not your fault.
- 就是我的错 - 不
- But it is. - No.
是我的错
This one's on me.
是我指引了他们
I showed 'em the way.
听着
Well, listen,
我们以后有的是时间
you and I are gonna have plenty of time
- 争论谁对谁错 - 如果还有以后的话
- to talk about this later. - If there is a later.
当然有了
Yes, there is.
我的小屋还没建好呢
I got a cabin to finish.
那是什么
What is that?
瞧瞧谁醒了
Well, look who just woke up.
我们有办法出去了
We're getting out of here.
欢迎
Welcome...
女士们 先生们
ladies, gentlemen,
在这美妙的夜晚相聚在此
to this extraordinary evening.
让我们直奔主题
Let's dive right in
请出一号拍品
with lot number one...
甲龙
the ankylosaurus.
她属于四足食草恐龙
She's a herbivorous quadruped,
- 天啊 - 生活在白垩纪晚期
- I'll be damned! - late Cretaceous.
这是最大的装甲恐龙之一
This is one of the largest armored dinosaurs,
被古生物学家们誉为
known by paleontologists
"活体坦克"
as a living tank.
你在干什么
What are you doing?
逃跑
Escaping.
- 你有把握吗 - 没有
- You sure about this? - Nope.
现在是四百万美元 有人出五百万吗
I have $4 million. Anyone with five?
- 五百万美元 - 五百万美元
- $5 million. - $5 million.
五百万 有人出六百万吗
$5 million. Do I hear six?
- 六百万 - 六百万美元 谢谢
- $6 million! - $6 million. Thank you.
还有高于六… 七百万
Any increase on six... Seven.
- 七百万 - 八百万
- $7 million. - $8 million, now!
八百万美元 来电出价九百万
$8 million. $9 million on the phones.
有人出一千万吗
Do I hear $10 million?
- 一千万 一千万 - 一千万
- $10 million? $10 million? - Ten!
一千万美元 一次 两次
$10 million! Once, twice...
成交 这位来自印度尼西亚的先生
Sold... to the gentleman from Indonesia.
恭喜你 先生
Congratulations, sir.
女士们先生们 下面请出二号拍品
Lot number two, ladies and gentlemen.
一只幼年
A juvenile...
易特龙
allosaurus.
这是一种
A fierce...
极其凶猛的食肉恐龙
and an aggressive predator.
成交
Sold!
真精彩
Wonderful.
真是精彩的竞拍
Wonderful bidding.
- 装好了 出发吧 - 出发吧
- You're good. Let's go. - Move it out.
- 我们走 - 装好货 出发
- Here we go. - Bring it on back. Let's go.
好吧
Okay.
嘿 你
Hey. Hey, you.
看着我 看着我
Look at me. Look at me.
嘿
Hey!
跟我来 跟我来
Come with me. Come with me.
好了 这就对了
Okay. There you go.
不用谢我
You're welcome.
嘿 等等
Hey! Wait!
拜托 等一下
Please! Please wait.
她是洛克伍德的外孙女
That's Lockwood's granddaughter.
嘿
Hey.
孩子 你想从那里下来吗
Hey, kid. You want to come down out of there?
你还记得我吗
Do you remember me?
我叫克莱尔 你叫什么
My name is Claire. What's yours?
梅茜
Maisie.
- 梅茜·洛克伍德 - 梅茜
- Maisie Lockwood. - Oh, Maisie.
这是我朋友 欧文
Well, this is my friend, Owen.
我见过你跟迅猛龙在一起
I saw you with the velociraptors.
还有布鲁
Uh, Blue.
是吗
Oh. Oh, yeah?
你喜欢恐龙吗
Uh... y-you like dinosaurs?
我也喜欢
Hey, so do I.
这样吧 你从那儿出来
Tell you what, you come on down from there,
我给你好好讲讲布鲁的故事
I'll tell you everything you need to know about Blue, huh?
你看行吗
That sound all right?
太好了
All right, yeah.
出来吧
Come on down.
亲爱的
Sweetie...
我们需要你帮忙找到你的外公
we need some help finding your grandfather.
你能带我们去找他吗
Can you take us to him?
不
No.
你自己一个人跑到这的 对吗
You made it down here all by yourself, huh?
真勇敢 你需要有个朋友帮帮你
Brave kid. Looks like you could use a friend.
他去世了
He's gone.
听着 这样吧
so, listen, I'll tell you what,
我们现在要去找我们的朋友
we were just about to go and find our friends
然后离开这鬼地方
and then get the heck out of here.
你愿意跟我们一起走吗
You want to come with us?
我们也需要朋友
We could use a friend, too.
一千九百五十万 一千九百五十万
Nineteen-five! 19.5 right here.
有人出两千万吗 有人出两千万吗
Do I hear 20? Do I hear 20?
两千万吗 谢谢
20? Thank you.
谢谢 目前是两千万
Thank you. 20.
- 有人出… - 两千一百万
- Do I hear... - 21!
两千一百万 一次
$21 million!
两次
$21 million...
成交
Sold!
现在 女士们先生们
And now, ladies and gentlemen,
今晚的拍卖会 已经行至半程
that we are halfway through the evening...
我们将为诸位
...we'd like to offer a special treat
独具慧眼的买家
to our...
献上一个特别环节
discriminating buyers.
请大家提前一睹
This evening we will preview
我们正在研发的新产品\
a new asset that we've been developing.
它是用之前物种的碎片
A creature of the future
创造出来的未来生物
made from pieces of the past.
女士们先生们 请小心
Ladies and gentlemen, please be warned,
它完美融合了 地球上有史以来最危险的
this is the perfect blend of the two most dangerous creatures
两种生物
that have ever walked the Earth.
我们将它命名为
We call it...
暴虐迅猛龙
the Indoraptor.
用于现代战争的完美武器
The perfect weapon for the modern age.
只为战斗而生
Built for combat,
拥有比人类士兵更加敏锐的战术反应能力
with tactical responses more acute than any human soldier.
那是什么东西
What is that thing?
是他们造出来的
They made it.
米尔顿先生和另一个人造的
Mr. Mills and the other man.
什么人
What man?
他
Him.
由亨利·吴先生设计
Designed by Mr. Henry Wu,
它拥有和迅猛龙相当的高智商
with an intelligence quotient comparable to the velociraptor,
在生物性能方面 提高了嗅觉灵敏度
biospecs include a heightened sense of smell,
经过训练 能配合脉冲编码
and trained to respond to a pulse-coded
激光瞄准 系统行动
laser targeting system,
即使在复杂的环境中
enabling it to isolate and track prey
也能选出猎物进行追踪
in complex environments.
请看
Voilà!
首先 用激光标记目标
Now, first the laser sets the target.
锁定目标后
And then once locked on,
利用声音触发攻击性行为
the acoustic signal triggers the attack.
这只动物天性凶残好斗
This animal is relentless.
现在 改良工作还在进行之中
Now, modifications are still being made...
我出两千万
$20 millions!
不 这只是一件原型
No, th-this is a-a prototype.
不参与拍卖
Uh, not for sale.
两千一百万
21!
它目前…
it is still a...
- 还是原型 - 两千二百万
- a prototype, - 22!
但是
but...
两千三百万
23!
两千四百万
24!
两千四百万美元
$24 million.
两千五百万
$25 millions!
有人出两千六百万吗
Do I hear 26?
不能这东西离开这里半步
That thing can't leave this building.
- 两千六百万 - 有高于两千六百万的吗
- 26! - Any advance on 26?
- 两千七百万 - 你在干什么
- $27 million dollars. - What are you doing?
这只动物不能对外出售
This animal is not for sale.
先让他们尝到甜头
If you want to create an addict,
他们以后就会常来买的
you have to give them a taste.
他只是原型
He's a prototype.
这个原型现在已经卖到两千八百万美元了
Look, this prototype is worth $28 million right now.
放松点 我们还能造更多
Relax. We'll make some more.
他们也能
So will they.
嘿 兄弟
Hey, buddy.
咱们是不是想到一块儿去了
You thinking what I'm thinking?
一次 两次
Once, twice...
成交 恭喜这位来自俄国的朋友
Sold to the Russian friend.
你拍得这只惊世骇俗的动物
A congratulations for this magnificent animal.
快让开
Get out of the way!
快走
Go, go!
快把这东西弄走
Get this thing out of here!
米尔斯
Mills!
米尔斯 你在哪儿
Mills, where are you?!
我来拿我的奖金了
I want my bonus!
天啊
Holy cow.
你是什么恐龙
What are you?
我没在岛上见过你
I didn't see you on the island.
你真是个厉害的家伙
Oh, you're a tough guy.
瞧瞧你
Look at you.
看来是个改良品种
You're some kind of hot rod
肯定有一口漂亮的牙齿
with really pretty teeth.
这将成为我项链上完美的部件
This will make a perfect centerpiece for my necklace.
张开嘴
Oh, boy.
让开 让开
Move! Move! Out of the way!
不要
Don't!
你们两个真是天生一对
You two, you... deserve each other.
梅茜 过来
Maisie, come with me.
你拿到钱了
You got your money.
快滚吧
Now, walk away.
你们还想干嘛
Oh, what are you gonna do, huh?
我们要阻止这一切
We're gonna stop this. All of it.
怎么做
How?!
你们打算回到过去阻止哈蒙德违背天理吗
What, are you gonna go back in time before Hammond decided to play God?
泼出去的水收不回来了
You can't put it back in the box!
- 那也得试试 - 太迟了
- We have to try. - It's too late.
梅茜 过来
Maisie, come.
你们打算照顾她了 是吗
so you're gonna take care of her now, huh?
你们根本不知道她到底是什么
You have no idea what she is.
你们觉得哈蒙德跟洛克伍德是怎么决裂的
What do you think drove Hammond and Lockwood apart? Huh?
洛克伍德压根就没有什么外孙女
Lockwood never had a grandchild.
他只想要复活他的女儿
He just wanted his daughter back.
当时他掌握了这项技术
And he had the technology.
于是他又造了一个
He created another.
让她再一次诞生于世
He made her again.
快走
Go, go, go.
Come on!
快走
Come on.
把这个送去给米尔斯
Get this to Mills.
千万当心 这非常珍贵
Be very careful... it's extremely valuable.
你 我需要这迅猛龙的血液样本
You... I need blood samples from the raptor.
还愣在这干什么
Don't just stand there like an idiot!
快去给我50cc芬太尼和静脉采血工具来
Get me 50cc's carfentanil and a phlebotomy kit!
就在那边 快去
It's right there! Now!
快点 快点
Come on, come on.
我需要这头迅猛龙的血样
I need this raptor's blood.
我的天
Oh! For God...
好啊 请便
Sure, go ahead.
我要的东西呢
Where is that kit?!
好吧 听我说
Okay, now, listen to me.
你最好还是乖乖配合
It is better for you to cooperate.
但不管你帮不帮忙 这血样我都要定了
I'm gonna get this blood, with or without your help.
她的血已经不纯了
This blood's contaminated.
这只动物是我亲自设计的
I designed this animal myself.
绝对是绝种
It's pure.
她的每一个细胞
Every cell of her body
都是在最严格的环境中
was created in the most controlled environment,
最苛刻的条件下创造出来的
under the most demanding of conditions.
是啊 但我用霸王龙给她输过血了
Yeah, but I did an intravenous blood transfusion with a T. rex,
所以现在已经不纯了
So... it's a sock drawer in there.
你干了什么
You what?
富兰克林 你在干吗
Whoa! Frank! What are you doing?!
我在救你
Saving your life.
真棒
Yes!
站住
Stop!
不许动
Don't move.
离那个笼子远一点
Now, step away from that cage.
快点
Now.
冷静点
Easy, now.
快跑 快跑
Run. Run!
(易燃气体)
(中央控制室  检测到氰化氢)
(注意有毒)
戴夫 收到了吗
Dave, you copy?
戴夫 听到了吗
Dave, you there?
快跑
Run!
(照明控制系统)
(正在关闭系统)
你看到了吗
You see that?
氰化氢泄露
That's hydrogen cyanide.
如果超过控制等级所有恐龙都会死
If it reaches the containment level,it'll kill them all.
(空调系统故障)
通风系统出故障了
The ventilation system is down.
你能把它修好吗
Can you bring it back up?
服务器没有反应
The server's unresponsive.
必须重启整个系统
I have to reboot the whole system.
- 那就快重启 - 我在试
- So reboot it. - I'm trying.
什么
What?
富兰克林 没时间了
Franklin, we don't have time.
我知道
I know, I know, I know.
好了
Okay.
(正在重启)
快跑 快跑
Come on. Go! Go, run, run!
嘿
Hey.
没事了
You're okay.
用手按住 别去看
Put pressure on it. Don't look at it.
看着我 看着我
Look at me. Look at me.
你得去找她
You have to go find her.
我不能把你留在这
I can't leave you here.
去吧 我没事的
Go. I'll be fine.
快去
Run!
梅茜 卧倒
Maisie! Stay down!
跟我来
Follow me.
我知道另一边有条路
I know a way on the other side.
快点
Come on.
快
Come on!
这边
This way!
我抓住你了
I got ya!
嘿
Hey!
这是怎么了
What the hell?
嘿
Hey!
你们还好吗
You good?
挺好 你们呢
Yeah. You?
不好
Nope.
嘿 下面出了点状况
Hey, we got a problem downstairs.
你们得下来看看
I need you to come see this.
它们快死了
They're all dying.
爆炸损坏了通风系统
The blast damaged the ventilation system.
能试的我们都试过了
We did everything we could.
我可以从这里打开闸门
I can open the gates from here.
克莱尔 想清楚
Claire. Be careful.
我们现在可不是在岛上了
We're not on an island anymore.
(闸门锁定)
(闸门开启)
(紧急按钮  开启外层闸门)
克莱尔
Claire.
一旦按下去就再也不能回头了
You press that button, there is no going back.
我们不能看着它们死
We can't let them die.
我必须这么做
I had to.
它们是有的生命 跟我一样
They're alive, like me.
不 不
No! No!
嘿 小妞
Hey, girl.
欧文
Owen.
没事 她不会伤害我们的
It's okay. She won't hurt us.
布鲁 跟我来吧
Blue, come with me.
我们带你去一个安全的地方 好吗
We'll take you to a safe place, okay?
你们还要多少事例来证明
How many times do you have to see the evidence?
这样的话还要重复多少遍
How many times must the point be made?
我们这是在自取灭亡
We're causing our own extinction.
跨越了太多不该跨越的界限
Too many red lines have been crossed.
我们的家园 从根本上来说
And our home has,in fundamental ways,
已经彻底被我们自身的贪婪和权欲所污染
been polluted by avarice and political megalomania.
基因力量好比潘多拉魔盒
Genetic power has now been unleashed,
一旦开启必将带来灾难
and of course, that's gonna be catastrophic.
从第一只再生恐龙诞生那刻起
This change was inevitable from the moment
这种改变已经不可避免
we brought the first dinosaur back from extinction.
我们总以为所谓的突变
We convince ourselves that sudden change
是那些跳脱事物秩序的情况
is something that happens outside the normal order of things,
就像… 车祸
like a... car crash,
或者是超出我们控制的 就像绝症
or that it's beyond our control, like a fatal illness.
我们从未意识到如此不合常理的巨大改变
We don't conceive of sudden, radical, irrational change
会发生在现实生活中
as woven into the very fabric of existence.
但我向各位保证 现实就是如此
Yet, I can assure you, it most assuredly is.
改变正在发生
And it's happening now.
人类和恐龙不得不设法共存
Humans and dinosaurs are now gonna be forced to coexist.
这些生物的出现远早于我们
These creatures were here before us.
如果我们不谨慎对待 灭绝的将是我们
And if we're not careful, they're gonna be here after.
我们要学会适应这些超乎想象的威胁
We're gonna have to adjust to new threats that we can't imagine.
人类进入了一个新纪元
We've entered a new era.
欢迎来到侏罗纪世界
Welcome to Jurassic World.